[
    {
        "question": "Acetaminophen",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Acetaminophen</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tylenol&reg;, Abenol&reg;, Acet&reg;, Tempral&reg;, Atasol&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Nonnarcotic Analgesic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>OTC</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain, Fever</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Chewable Tablet, Suppository</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Supp: 120 mg, 160 mg, 325 mg, 650 mg. Chew tab: 80 mg, 160 mg. Tab: 160 mg, 325 mg, 500 mg, 650 mg. Solution: 80 mg/mL, 160 mg/5 mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Derm: pruritis. GI: constipation, nausea, vomiting. CNS: headache, insomnia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hepatotoxicity may occur after ingestion of a single dose of more than 7.5 g (adults) or 150 mg/kg (children); a dose of 10 g or more is potentially fatal in an adult. Acetylcysteine used in acute overdose. Because of the risk of toxicity, dosing for children must not exceed 5 doses in 24 hours unless under the advice of a physician.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acetaminophen / Caffeine / Codeine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Acetaminophen / Caffeine / Codeine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Exdol&reg;, Acet 2&reg;, Acet 3&reg;, Tylenol with Codeine&reg;, Novo-Gesic C&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Opiate Analgesic Combination</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA I</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Elixir</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>325/30/8 mg, 325/30/15 mg, 325/30/30 mg, 300 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Every 4 Hours, Every 6 Hours</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Most frequent adverse effects: drowsiness, lightheadedness, dizziness, sedation, shortness of breath, nausea, vomiting (more prominent in ambulatory patients). Constipation and abdmonial pain are common.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Monitor total acetaminophen intake (including other acetaminophen-containing products) to assure maximum dose is not exceeded. CNS effects enhanced by other CNS depressants.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asaphen&reg;, Bufferin&reg;, Entrophen&reg;, Novasen ECT&reg;, Anacin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Salicylate NSAID</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>OTC</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiplatelet agent; pain, fever, inflammation</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Chewable Tablet, Suppository</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>supp: 150 mg, 650 mg. chew tab: 80 mg. tab: 75 mg, 81 mg, 162 mg, 325 mg , 500 mg, 650 mg, 975 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: Nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, dyspepsia, bleeding and/or ulceration. CNS: tinnitus occurs with large doses.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>NSAIDs (reversible COX inhibitors) may interfere with antplatelet effects of aspirin via competative inhibition. When used for antiplatelet effects, aspirin should be taken 30-120 minutes before a NSAID. Do not use in children/teens with viral ifection (risk of Reye's syndrome). Contraindicated in last trimester of pregnancy.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alendronate",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Alendronate</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Fosamax&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bisphosphonate</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Osteoporosis, Paget's Disease of the Bone</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Oral Solution</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>40 mg, 70 mg, 70 mg/75 mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Once Weekly</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Upper GI disorders (dysphagia, esophagitis, esophageal ulcer and gastric ulcer may occur), musculoskeletal pain, abdominal pain, dyspepsia and nausea, diarrhea.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Should be taken on an empty stomach at least 30 minutes before consuming the first food, drink (other than plain water) and/or any other medication of the day. Food, medication or drink other than plain water can interfere with the absorption.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Allopurinol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Allopurinol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Zyloprim&reg;, Alloprin&reg;, Teva-Purol&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Xanthine Oxidase Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Gout</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>100 mg, 200 mg, </td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily, Three Times Daily, (Doses >300 mg should be divided)</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Skin rash (including Stevens-Johnson syndrome), usually maculopapular, is the most commonly reported adverse effect. Incidence of skin rash may be increased with renal disorders. GI (Diarrhea, intermittent abdominal pain, nausea and vomiting) side effects are common.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Better tolerated when taken with food. Dosage adjustment required in renal dysfunction.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amitriptyline",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Amitriptyline</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Elavil&reg;, Levate&reg;, Teva-Tryptin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tricyclic antidepressant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, Unlabeled uses: pain, migraine prophyaxis, neuropathy</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 25 mg, 50 mg, 75 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, usually taken HS</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticholinergic: dry mouth, urinary retention, constipation. CNS: drowsiness, fatigue. CV: othostatic hypotension, tachycardia. Weight gain is common.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Extremely toxic in overdose: arrhythmia, hypotension, seizures, acidosis. Drug interactions common: CYP 2D6 substrate.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amlodipine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Amlodipine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Norvasc&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Calcium Channel Blocker (Dihydropiridine)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>HTN, chronic stable angina</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>2.5 mg, 5 mg, 10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: edema, postural dizziness. CNS: Headache. GI: has been associated with gingical hyperplasia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with atorvastatin (Caduet). Drug interactions: CYP 3A4 substrate.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amoxicillin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Amoxicillin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tevamoxin&reg;, Pro-Amox&reg;, Nu-Amoxi&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antibiotic (Semisynthetic Penicillin)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bacterial infection: Upper respiratiry tract. Lower respiratory tract, UTI, H pylori, Lyme disease</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule, Oral Suspesion, Chewable Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>125 mg/5 mL, 250 mg/5 mL, 125 mg, 250 mg, 500 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Every 8 Hours, single dose for endocarditis prevention (prior to procedure)</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Derm: allergic rash (usually erythematous, urticarial, may be maculopapular); incidence increased in mononucleosis. GI: nausea, vomiting, diarrhea. Renal: has been associated with acute interstitial neprhitis (uncommon).</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Probenecid inhibits renal tubular excretion (â†‘ amoxicillin concentrations). Associated with decreased oral contraceptive efficacy by reducing bacteria responsible for enterohepatic recirculation of estrogen.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atenolol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Atenolol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tenormin&reg;, Nu-Atenol&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Beta blocker (Î²-1 selective)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>HTN, angina, secondary prevention post MI</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mg, 50 mg, 100 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Resp: broconchospasm. CV: hypotension, worsening of HF, bradycardia, heart block. CNS: fatigue, depression. Other: sexual dysfunction in males.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: use with caution with other negative chronotropes (nondihydroipyridine CCBs, digoxin, Class I antiarrhythmics, amiodarone). If used in combination with clonidine, Î²-blocker should be withdrawn before stopping clonidine (overstimulation of upregulated Î²-receptors upon clonidine withdrawal may exacerbate rebound HTN).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Atorvastatin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Atorvastatin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lipitor&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antihyperlipidemic Agent (HMG-CoA Reductase Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dyslipidemia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 20 mg, 40 mg, 80 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Skeletal: musculoseketal pain, rhabdomyolysis (rare), GI: liver funtion abnormalities.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with amlodipine (Caduet). Drug interactions: CYP 3A4 substrate. Use with caution with other agents associated with myopathy/rhabdomyolysis (e.g., fibric acid derivatives).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Azithromycin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Azithromycin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Zithromax&reg;, Zmax SR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antibiotic (macrolide)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bacterial infection: Upper and lower respiratory tract infection, STD (chlamydia, gonorrhea), uncomplicated skin soft tissue, prevention of MAC</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Oral Suspesion, Granules</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>250 mg, 600 mg, 100 mg/5 mL, 200 mg/5 mL, 500 mg vial for injection</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, single dose for chlamydia, once weekly for MAC prophylaxis</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: loose stools/diarrhea, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>The 250 mg tablets are available in a unit-of-use package known as Z-Pak (duration of therapy 5 days). Zmax SR contains sustained release granules for oral suspention.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bisoprolol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bisoprolol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Monocor&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Beta blocker (Î²-1 selective)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, heart failure, angina</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>5 mg, 10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Resp: broconchospasm. CV: hypotension, worsening of HF, bradycardia, heart block. CNS: fatigue, depression. Other: sexual dysfunction in males.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Heart failure and angina are not approved indications in Canada. Drug interactions: use with caution with other negative chronotropes (nondihydroipyridine CCBs, digoxin, Class I antiarrhythmics, amiodarone). If used in combination with clonidine, Î²-blocker should be withdrawn before stopping clonidine (overstimulation of upregulated Î²-receptors upon clonidine withdrawal may exacerbate rebound HTN).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Budesonide / Formoterol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Budesonide / Formoterol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Symbicort&reg;, Symbicort Forte&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Corticosteroid / Long Acting Beta Agonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asthma, COPD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>DPI</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>100 mcg/6 mcg, 200 mcg/6 mcg, 400 mgc/12 mcg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cardiac: palpitations. CNS: Headache, tremor. Infection: oral candidiasis (thrush). ENT: cough, hoarseness.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asthma indication for age 12 and above. LABA may increase risk of asthma related death, particularly in pediatric and adolescent patients. Counsel patients to rinse mouth after use.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bupropion",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bupropion</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Wellbutrin&reg;, Wellbutrin SR&reg;, Wellbutrin XL&reg;, Zyban&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (aminoketone)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, seasonal affective disorder (SAD), smoking cessation</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>100 mg SR, 150 mg SR, 150 mg XL, 300 mg XL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily, Three Times Daily, depending on dosage form</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cardiac: tachycardia. CNS: headache, insomnia, dizziness. GI: dry mouth, constipation, nausea. EENT: tinnitus.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>SR formulation dosed BID; XL formulation dosed once daily. Drug interactions:bupropion inhibits CYP 2D6--use with caution in combination with 2D6 substrates. Co-administration of thioridazine (QTc prolongation) and MAO inhibitors is contraindicated.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Candesartan",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Candesartan</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Atacand&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, heart failure</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>4 mg, 8 mg, 16 mg, 32 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Also available combined with HCTZ (Atacand Plus). Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesartan efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Celecoxib",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Celecoxib</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Celebrex&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiinflammatory (NSAID)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Rheumatoid arthritis, osteoarthritis, acute pain, ankylosing spondylitis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>100 mg, 200 mg, 300 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: Peripheral edema. CNS: dizziness, insomnia. GI: abdominal pain, diarrhea, dyspepsia, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Celecoxib is a specific inhibitor of cyclooxygenase-2. May increase the risk of CV events. Cross sensitivity with sulfonamides.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cephalexin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cephalexin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Keflex&reg; Apo-Cephalex&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antibiotic (cephalosporin)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Uncomplicated skin/soft tissue infection, URI, acute cystitis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Capsule, Oral Suspesion</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>250 mg, 500 mg, 125 mg/5 mL, 250 mg/5 mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Four Times Daily, Every 6 Hours</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: Nausea, vomiting, diarrhea (usually transient and mild). Has been associated with serum sickness-like reactions.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interaction: probenecid inhibits tubular secretion and decreases cephalexin elimination.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ciprofloxacin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ciprofloxacin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cipro&reg;, Cipro XL&reg;, Ciloxan&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antibiotic (fluoroquinolone)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Respiratory tract infection, UTI, prostatitis, skin/soft tissue infection, bone/joint infection, infectious diarrhea, gonorrhea</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, Injection, Ophthalmic Solution, Oral Suspesion, Ophthalmic Ointment</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>250 mg, 500 mg, 750 mg, 500 mg XL, 1000 mg XL, 500 mg/5 mL, 0.3% ophth, 200 mg/mL inj</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily, single dose for gonorrhea</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: nausea, diarrhea. CNS: dizziness, nervousness, insomnia. May cause seizures in predisposed individuals. May cause photosensitivity.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Each package for oral suspension contains microcapsules of ciprofloxacin along with a diluent. Water should not be used to form the suspension. Cipro Oral Suspension is stable for 14 days when stored under refrigeration or at room temperature. Drug interactions: potent inhibitor of CYP 1A2. May cause muscle weakness in patients with myesthenia gravis. Reports of tendon rupture. Safety under age 18 not established.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Citalopram",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Citalopram</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Celexa&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 20 mg, 40 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: insomnia, somnolence. GI: nausea, diarrhea, dry mouth. CV: postural hypotension, tachycardia. GU: sexual dysfunction, decreased libido.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Citalopram is a racemic mixture. The S-isomer is responsible for antidepressant effects, while the R-isomer may contribute to adverse effects. Drug interactions: use with caution with other agents that prolong QTc and agents that increase serotonin. Citalopram is a substrate for CYP 2C19 and 3A4--overall risk of interactions is low.  </td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clarithromycin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Clarithromycin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Biaxin&reg;, Biaxin XL&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antibiotic (macrolide)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Upper and lower respiratory tract infection, skin/soft tissue infection, Mycobacterium avium complex</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, Oral Suspesion</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>250 mg, 500 mg, 500 mg XL, 125 mg/5 mL, 250 mg/5 mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily, depending on dosage form</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: taste disturbance, diarrhea, vomiting, nausea. CNS: headache.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Biaxin oral suspension maintains stability for 14 days when stored at room temperature â€“ the reconstituted suspension may form a gel if stored under refrigeration. Drug interactions: Inhibitor of CYP 3A and P glycoprotein. Contraindicated with lovastatin, simvastatin, ergotamine, dihydroergotamine, pimozide.  </td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clonazepam",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Clonazepam</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Rivotril&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Benzodiazepine</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA IV</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Seizures</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.25 mg, 0.5 mg, 1 mg, 2 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Three Times Daily, dosing for unlabelled uses is variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: drowsiness, fatigue, somnolence, dizziness. Associated with anterograde amnesia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Many unlabelled uses: restless legs syndrome, panic, insomnia. Drug interactions: substrate for CYP 3A4. Combination with CNS depressants (including alcohol) may enhance toxicity of both agents.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Clopidogrel",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Clopidogrel</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Plavix&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiplatelet Agent (thienopyridine)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Secondary prevention of atherothrombotic events in patients with a recent MI or stroke, or have peripheral arterial disease. Management of ACS. Primary prevention of stroke in atrial fib</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>75 mg, 300 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hematologic: bleeding, bruising, epistxias. Dermatologic: rash.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Clopidogrel is a prodrug converted to active form by CYP 2C19--inhibitors of 2C19 may decrease efficacy (especially imporatant in 2C19 poor metabolizers).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Conjugate Estrogens",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Conjugate Estrogens</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Premarin&reg;, C.E.S.&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Estrogen</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Menopausal symptoms, atrophic vaginitis, osteoporosis prevention</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Vaginal Cream</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.3 mg, 0.625 mg, 0.9 mg, 1.25 mg, 2.5 mg, 0.625 mg/g vaginal cream, 25 mg via</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: Increased blood pressure. GI: abdominal pain. CNS: dizziness, nervousness.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Causes hypercoagulability and increases risk of VTE. increased risk of CHD in postmenopausal women (HERS, HERS II, WHI studies). increased risk of breast cancer. Increased risk of enometrial cancer if not taken in conjunction with progesterone.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cyclobenzaprine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cyclobenzaprine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Teva-Cyclobenzaprine&reg;, Apo, Cyclobenzaprine&reg; (Flexeril&reg;)</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Skeletal muscle relaxant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Muscle spasm (short term use). Unlabelled use: fibromyalgia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Three Times Daily, may be dosed once daily HS or BID in fibromyalgia</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: drowsiness, fatigue, dizziness. GI: dry mouth.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: substrate for CYP 1A2, 3A4, 2D6. Use with caution with other anticholinergic or serotinergic agents.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Diclofenac",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diclofenac</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Voltaren Emulgel&reg;, Voltaren Rapide&reg;, Voltaren&reg;, Voltaren Ophtha&reg;, Pennsaid&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiinflammatory (NSAID)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL, OTC (see column called 'Other')</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>RA/OA (Na+ salt), short term for inflammation and pain (K+ salt)</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, Ophthalmic Solution, Topical Gel, Suppository</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral: 25 mg, 50 mg, 75 mg SR, 100 mg SR. Topical: 1.16% Gel, 1.5% solution. Supp: 50 mg, 100 mg, ophth: 0.1%</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily, Three Times Daily, rapid release used every 6- 8 hours</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: Edema. CNS: dizziness, headache. Derm: rash. GI: abdominal pain, constipation, heartburn, nausea, peptic ulcer/GI bleed. Heme: bleeding.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Voltaren Emulgel is OTC. Potassium salt rapid release, sodium salt enteric coated or SR. May attenuate effects of antihypertensives, particularly ACE inhibitors and ARBs. Avoid use in renal dysfunction and heart failure. Contraindicated in last trimester of pregnancy.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Diclofenac / Misoprostol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diclofenac / Misoprostol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Arthrotec&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiinflammatory (NSAID)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Rheumatoid arthritis, osteoarthritis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>50 mg/200 mcg, 75 mg/200 mcg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily, Three Times Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: abdominal pain, diarrhea, nausea, dyspepsia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Misoprostol added to decrease risk of GI injury. Should be taken immediately after a meal or with food/milk. Contraindicated in pregnancy (abortifacient potential). May attenuate effects of antihypertensives, particularly ACE inhibitors and ARBs. Avoid use in renal dysfunction and heart failure.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Digoxin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Digoxin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lanoxin&reg;, Toloxin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cardiac Glycoside</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Heart failure, rate control in atrial fib</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Oral Solution</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral: 0.0625 mg, 0.125 mg, 0.25 mg, 0.05 mg/mL. Injection: 0.05 mg/mL, 0.25 mg/mL, 0.05 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: dizziness, confusion. GI: nausea, vomoting, diarrhea, anorexia. Ocular: blurred vision/yellow halo with toxicity. CV: AV block, bradycardia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>The normal digoxin serum level for treatment of heart failure is 0.5 â€“ 0.8 ng/mL (toxicity common with concentrations > 2 ng/mL). Drug interactions: quinidine, verapamil, amiodarone, propafenone, indomethacin, itraconazole, alprazolam, and spironolactone raise the serum digoxin concentration due to a reduction in clearance and/or in volume of distribution of the drug.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Diltiazem",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diltiazem</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cardizem LA&reg;, Cardizem CD&reg;, Tiazac&reg;, Apo-Diltiaz&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Calcium Channel Blocking Agent (non-dihydropyridine)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, angina, rate control in a fib, SVT</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, ER Capsule, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral: 30 mg, 60 mg, 90 mg, 120 mg ER, 180 mg ER, 240 mg ER, 300 mg ER, 360 mg ER. Injection: 5 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing varies with dosage form, Injection via continuous infusion</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: edema, hypotension, heart block. CNS: headache. GI: constipation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: major substrate and moderate inhibitor of CYP 3A4.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Divalproex",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Divalproex</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Epival&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticonvulsant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Epilepsy, Bipolar disorder</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>125 mg, 250 mg, 500 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily, Three Times Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache, somnolence, dizziness, insomnia. Derm: alopecia. GI: weight gain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea. Heme: thrombocytopenia (dose-related).</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Minor substrate of multiple enzymes. Moderate inhibitor of CYP 2A6.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Domperidone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Domperidone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Apo-Domperidone&reg;, Teva-Domperidone&reg;, (Motilium&reg;)</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI Motility Agent</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Upper GI motility disorders, gastroparesis. Unlabelled uses: GERD, chemotherapy induced N/V, improve lactation in nursing mothers (dopaminergic)</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Three Times Daily, Four Times Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. GI: dry mouth, abdominal cramping. Endocrine: galactorrhea.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>If used for gastroparesis, should be taken 15-30 minutes prior to eating. Associated with ventricula arrhythmias. Avoid use with agents that prolong QTc.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Donepezil",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Donepezil</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Aricept&reg;, Aricept RDT&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cholinesterase Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Alzheimerâ€™s disease</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ODS</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>5 mg and10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: insomnia. GI: nausea (dose related), diarrhea (dose related), anorexia. GU: urinary frequency, incontinence.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Maximum dose in elderly women with low body weight is 5 mg. Increases acetylcholine concentrations: use with caution in bradycardia (vagal stimulation lowering HR) and risk of PUD (increeased gastric acid secretion). Drug interactions: avoid anticholinergic drugs (attenuate effect of donepezil).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Duloxetine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Duloxetine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cymbalta&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (Selective Serotonin Norepinephrine Reuptake Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, generalized anxiety disorder, diabetic peripheral neuropathy, fibromyalgia, chronic low back pain, osteoarthritis of the knee</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>30 mg and 60 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: somnolence, dizziness, tremor. GI: nausea, dry mouth, anorexia, constipation. GU: abnormal ejaculation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: use with caution with agents that increase serotonin. Substrate for CYP 1A2 and CYP 2D6 and inhibitor of CYP 2D6. Contraindicated with thioradazine (decreases metabolism of thioridazine and may increase QTc interval)</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Escitalopram",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Escitalopram</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cipralex&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, anxiety, OCD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg and 20 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: Headache, somnolence, insomnia. GI: Nausea, diarrhea, dry mouth. GU: decreased libido, anorgasmia, impotence.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug Interactions: escitalopram is a substrate for CYP 2C19 and 3A4--overall risk of interactions is low. Use with caution with agents that increase serotonin (risk for serotonin syndrome).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Esomeprazole",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Esomeprazole</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Nexium&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Proton Pump Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GERD, hypersecretory conditions, prevention of NSAID induced ulcers</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Tablet, Granules</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg granules for suspension, 20 mg, 40 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Some conditions require BID dosing (H pylori regimens, Zollinger Ellison)</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. GI: diarrhea, flatulance, nausea, vomiting, dry mouth.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Major substrate and moderate inhibitor of CYP 2C19. Product available combined with naproxen (Vimovo). Possible association with C. difficile associated diarrhea. May decrease effecacy of clopidogrel, particularly in CYP 2C19 slow metabolizers. May increase risk of osteoporosis related fractures.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Estradiol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Estradiol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Climara&reg;, Estraderm&reg;, Vagifem 10&reg;, Estring&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Estrogen</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Menopausal Symptoms</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Transdermal, Vaginal Insert, Vaginal Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>patch: 0.025 mg/24 hours, 0.0375mg/24 hours, 0.05mg/ 24 hours, 0.075 mg/24 hours, 0.1 mg/24 hours. Vaginal tablet: 10 mcg, 25 mcg. Vaginal ring: 2 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Weekly, Twice Weekly, patches vary in replacement frequency, Estraing replaced every 90 days</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: Increased blood pressure. GI: nausea, comiting, abdominal discomfort. CNS: dizziness, nervousness.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Causes hypercoagulability and increases risk of VTE. increased risk of CHD in postmenopausal women (HERS, HERS II, WHI studies). increased risk of breast cancer. Increased risk of enometrial cancer if not taken in conjunction with progesterone. Drug interactions: CYP 3A4 substrate.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ethinyl Estradiol / Desogestrel",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ethinyl Estradiol / Desogestrel</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Linessa&reg;, Marvelon&reg;, Ortho-cept&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Estrogen / Progesterone</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Contraception</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.03 mg/0.15mg, 0.025 mg/0.1 mg + 0.125 mg + 0.15 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: Nausea, vomiting, weight gain. GU: breakthrough bleeding, spotting, amenorrhea, breast tenderness, delayed return of fertility after discontinuation. Rare but serious CV: thromboembolism, MI, CVA.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cigarette smoking increases the risk of serious CV adverse effects, increasing with age 35 years. Women should be counselled not to smoke. Drug Interactions: OCP efficacy can be decreased by drugs that induce hepatic eznymes and agents that alter intestinal flora (interfere with enterohepatic circulation of hormones).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ethinyl Estradiol / Drospirenone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ethinyl Estradiol / Drospirenone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Yasmin&reg;, Yaz&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Estrogen / Progesterone</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Contraception</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.03mg/3 mg, 0.02 mg/3 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: Nausea, vomiting, weight gain. GU: breakthrough bleeding, spotting, amenorrhea, breast tenderness, delayed return of fertility after discontinuation. Rare but serious CV: thromboembolism, MI, CVA</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cigarette smoking increases the risk of serious CV adverse effects, increasing with age 35 years. Women should be counselled not to smoke. Drug Interactions: OCP efficacy can be decreased by drugs that induce hepatic eznymes and agents that alter intestinal flora (interfere with enterohepatic circulation of hormones). 3 mg drosperenone has antimineralocorticoid activity comparable to a 25 mg dose of spironolactone.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ethinyl Estradiol / Levonorgestrel",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ethinyl Estradiol / Levonorgestrel</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Alesse&reg;, Aviane&reg;, Min-Ovral&reg;, Portia&reg;, Seasonale&reg;, Seasonique&reg;, Triquilar&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Estrogen / Progesterone</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Contraceptive</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.02 mg/0.1 mg, 0.03 mg/0.15 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: Nausea, vomiting, weight gain. GU: breakthrough bleeding, spotting, amenorrhea, breast tenderness, delayed return of fertility after discontinuation. Rare but serious CV: thromboembolism, MI, CVA.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cigarette smoking increases the risk of serious CV adverse effects, increasing with age 35 years. Women should be counselled not to smoke. Drug Interactions: OCP efficacy can be decreased by drugs that induce hepatic eznymes and agents that alter intestinal flora (interfere with enterohepatic circulation of hormones).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ezetimibe",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ezetimibe</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ezetrol&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antihyperlipidemic Agent</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hyperlipidemia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: Fatigue. GI: Diarrhea.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: bile acid sequestrants may decrease ezetimibe concentrations; fibric acids may increase ezetimibe concentrations.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fenofibrate",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Fenofibrate</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Fenomax&reg;, Lipidil EZ&reg;, Lipidil Micro&reg;, Lipidil Supra&reg;, Pro-Feno-Super&reg;, Apo-Feno- Micro</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antihyperlipidemic Agent (Fibric Acid Derivative)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hyperlipidemia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>48 mg, 67 mg, 100 mg, 160 mg, 200 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: LFTs increased in up to 13% of patients, abdomnial pain, constipation, nausea. CNS: Headache.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: May increase anticoagulant effect of warfarin (may require 25-33% reduction in warfarin dose).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fluticasone / Salmeterol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Fluticasone / Salmeterol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Advair&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Corticosteroid / Long Acting Beta Agonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asthma, COPD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral Inhaler, DPI</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>100 mcg/50 mcg, 250 mcg/50 mcg, 500 mcg/50 mcg DPI; 125 mcg/25 mcg, 250 mcg/25 mcg MDI</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache, dizziness. Respiratory: URI, pharyngitis, cough, hoarseness/throat irritation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: salmeterol and fluticasone are CYP 3A4 substrates. Instruct patient to rinse mouth after use. Indicated in children 4 years and older.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fluticasone Oral Inhalation",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Fluticasone Oral Inhalation</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Flovent Discus&reg;, Flovent HF&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral Corticosteroid Inhalant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asthma Prophylaxis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral Inhaler, DPI</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>DPI: 50 mcg, 100 mcg, 250 mcg. MDI: 50 mcg, 125 mcg, 250 mcg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache, dizziness. Respiratory: URI, pharyngitis, cough, hoarseness/throat irritation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: CYP 3A4 substrate. Instruct patient to rinse mouth after use.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Furosemide",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Furosemide</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lasix&reg;, Lasix Special&reg;, Teva-Semide&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Loop Diuretic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, edema</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>20 mg, 40 mg, 80 mg, 500 mg, 10 mg/mL injection</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Metabolic: hypokalemia, hypomagnesemia, hyperuricemia. GI: anorexia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: May increase aminoglycoside ototoxicity, particularly in renal impairment. Cross sensitivity to sulfonamide-derivatives may occur.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gabapentin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Gabapentin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Neurontin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticonvulsant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Partial seizures, pain associated with postherpetic neuralgia (PHN)</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>100 mg, 300 mg, 400 mg, 600 mg, 800 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: dizziness, somnolence, fatige. CV: edema. GI: diarrhea, nausea/vomiting. Neuromuscular: tremor. Ocular: nystagmus.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Not metabolized to a significant extent and does not interfere with the metabolism of commonly administered antiepileptic drugs. Dosage adjusted in renal dysfunction.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gliclazide",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Gliclazide</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diamicron&reg;, Diamicron MR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sulfonylurea</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Type 2 diabetes</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>30 mg, 60 mg, 80 mg ER</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Metabolic: hypoglycemia. CV: edema. Derm: rash. GI (usually dose dependent): abdominal pain, constipation, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Gliclazide is a CYP 2C9 substrate. May potentiate effects of warfarin. Hypoglycemia may be potentiated by other agents that reduce glucose. Flushing may occur with alcohol. Cross reactivity with sulfonamides is possible (less common than with older agents).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Glyburide",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Glyburide</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diabeta&reg;, Euglucon&reg;, Mylan-Glybe&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sulfonylurea</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Type 2 diabetes</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>2.5 mg, 5 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Metabolic: hypoglycemia. CV: edema. Derm: rash. GI (usually dose dependent): abdominal pain, constipation, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: glyburide is a CYP 2C9 substrate. Hypoglycemia may be potentiated by other agents that reduce glucose (Serious and prolonged hypoglycemic events may occur in patients with renal or hepatic insufficiency ). Flushing may occur with alcohol. Cross reactivity with sulfonamides is possible (less common than with older agents).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydrochlorothiazide",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hydrochlorothiazide</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Teva-Hydrochlorothiazide&reg;, Nu-Hydro&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Thiazide diuretic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Edema associated with HF and cirrhosis; hypertension</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>12.5 mg, 25 mg, 50 mg, 100 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: hypotension, orthostasis. Derm: phtotoxicity, rash (including Stevens- Johnson). Metabolic: hypokalemia, hypomagnesemia, hyperuricemia</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: insulin/oral hypoglycemic effects may be diminished. May increase the likelihood of lithium toxicity.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hydromorphone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hydromorphone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dilaudid&reg;, Dilaudid HP&reg;, Dilaudid HPPlus&reg;, Dilaudid XP&reg;, Jurnista&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Opiate Analgesic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA I</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, Injection, Oral Solution, Suppository</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>1 mg, 2 mg, 4 mg, 8 mg, 4.5 mg ER, 9 mg ER, 12 mg ER, 18 mg ER, 24 mg ER, 1 mg/mL, 10 mg/mL inj, 20 mg/mL inj, 50 mg/mL inj, 3 mg supp</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: dizziness, drowsiness, somnolence, headache. GI: constipaiton, nausea, vomiting. Derm: flushing, sweating, itching.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS effects enhanced by other CNS depressants.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Irbesartan",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Irbesartan</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Avapro&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, reduce proteinuria in type 2 diabetes</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>75 mg, 150 mg, 300 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesartan efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in  pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lansoprazole",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lansoprazole</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Prevacid&reg;, Prevacid Fastab&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Proton Pump Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GERD, hypersecretory conditions, prevention of NSAID induced ulcers</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Capsule, ODS</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>15 mg, 30 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. GI: diarrhea, flatulance, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lansoprazole orally disintegrating tablets contain lansoprazole in enteric-coated microgranules. Drug interactions: Major substrate of CYP 2C19 and 3A4. Moderate inhibitor of CYP 2C19 and inducer of CYP 1A2. Possible association with C. difficile associated diarrhea. May decrease effecacy of clopidogrel, particularly in CYP 2C19 slow metabolizers. May increase risk of osteoporosis related fractures.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Latanoprost",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Latanoprost</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Xalatan&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Prostaglandin F analogue</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Glaucoma</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ophthalmic Solution</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>50 mcg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ocular: blurred vision, burning, stinging, itching., increased pigmenatation of the iris.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with timolol (Xalacom). Eye drops containing thimerosal may cause precipitation of latanoprost when coadministered--allow at least 5 minutes between applications.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Levothyroxine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Levothyroxine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Eltroxin&reg;, Synthroid&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Thyroid hormone</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypothyroidism</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mcg, 50 mcg, 88 mcg, 112 mcg, 100 mcg, 125 mcg, 137 mcg, 150 mcg, 175 mcg, 200 mcg, 300 mcg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Adverse reactions unrelated to excessive dosage (thyrotoxicosis) are rare. Excessive doage may result in tachycardia, hypertension, nervousness, anxiety, hair loss, decreased bone mineral density.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Food may decrease absorption. Instruct patient to take on an empty stomach at least 30 minutes before eating. Iron salts, calcium, bile acid sequestrants, and antacids should be separated from levothyroxine by at least 4 hours. The bioavailability of levothyroxine may differ among brands--caution should be exercised when a change in drug product occurs. Use with caution/initiate lower doses in elderly patients or those with CV disorders.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lorazepam",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lorazepam</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ativan&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Benzodiazepine</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA IV</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anxiety, seizures</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Sublingual Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.5 mg, 1 mg, 2 mg, 4 mg/mL inj</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: sedation, amnesia, depression, confusion, dizziness. Resp: respiratory depression (particularly when coadministered with other respiratory depressants). CV: hypotension.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Many unlabelled uses: restless legs syndrome, panic, insomnia. CNS effects enhanced by other CNS depressants. No active heaptic metaboliltes; therefore, less accumulation of effects than with many other benzodiazepines.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Losartan",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Losartan</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cozaar&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, reduce proteinuria in type 2 diabetes</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mg, 50 mg, 100 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'></td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Metformin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Metformin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Glucophage&reg;, Glumetza&reg;, Glycon&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidiabetic (Biguanide)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>500 mg, 850 mg, 1000 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily, Three Times Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: diarrhea, nausea/vomiting, flatulence. Skeletal: weakness.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Metformin unlikely to cause hypoglycemia when used as monotherapy, but may potentiate hypoglycemic effects of other glucose lowering agents. If radiocontrast media agents (known to alter renal function) are used, metformin should be discontinued at the time of the procedure and withheld for 48 hours. Metformin should be avoided in patients with CrCl < 60 mL/min.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Methylphenidate",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Methylphenidate</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Concerta&reg;, Biphentin&reg;, Riatlin&reg;, Ritalin- SR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Central Nervous System Stimulant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>G (CDSA III)</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, ER Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Concerta: 18 mg, 27 mg, 36 mg, 54 mg. Biphentin: 10 mg, 15 mg, 30 mg, 40 mg, 50mg, 60 mg, 80 mg. Ritalin: 10 mg, 20 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: anorexia, nausea, vomiting. CNS: headache, insomnia. Metabolic: weight loss. Psych: labile affect.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Food may increase absorption of some products.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Metoprolol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Metoprolol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lopressor&reg;, Lopressor SR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Beta Blocker (Î²-1 selective)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>HTN, angina, acute management of MI (IV), secondary prevention post MI</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>IR: 25 mg, 50 mg, 100 mg. SR: 100 mg, 200 mg. Inj: 1 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Resp: broconchospasm. CV: hypotension, worsening of HF, bradycardia, heart block. CNS: fatigue, depression. Other: sexual dysfunction in males.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Insoluble tablet core of SR formaulations may be seen in the feces. Drug interactions: use with caution with other negative chronotropes (nondihydroipyridine CCBs, digoxin, Class I antiarrhythmics, amiodarone). If used in combination with clonidine, Î²-blocker should be withdrawn before stopping clonidine (overstimulation of upregulated Î²-receptors upon clonidine withdrawal may exacerbate rebound HTN).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mirtazapine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Mirtazapine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Remeron&reg;, Remeron RD&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (tetracyclic)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>tablet 30 mg orally disintegrating tablet 15 mg, 30 mg, 45 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: somnolence, dizziness, abnormal dreams. Metabolic: increased cholesterol. GI: dry mouth, increased appetite, constipation, weith gain. GI: abdominal pain, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: CYP 1A2 and 2D6. Inhibits CYP 3A4. Sedation is more prominent at lower doses.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mometasone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Mometasone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asmanex Twisthaler&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral Corticosteroid Inhalant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asthma prophylaxis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>DPI</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>200 mcg, 400 mcg per inhalation</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. Respiratory: URI, pharyngitis, cough, hoarseness/throat irritation, oral candidiasis.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Not indicated for children <12 years. The 220 mcg strength is indicated for patients over 11 years old. Instruct patients to rinse mouth after use.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mometasone Nasal Inhalation",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Mometasone Nasal Inhalation</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Nasonex&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Corticosteroid</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Allergic rhinitis, acute rhinosinusitis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Nasal Inhaler</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>50 mcg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. Resp: pharyngitis, cough, nosebleed.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Indicated in children over the age of 3.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Montelukast",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Montelukast</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Singulair&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Leukotriene modifier</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Asthma, seasonal allergic rhinitis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Chewable Tablet, Granules</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Chew tab: 4 mg, 5 mg. Tab: 10 mg. Granules: 4 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, taken HS</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache, dizziness. Derm: rash. Hepatic: increased AST. Resp: cough, congestion.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Evening dosing has been employed so that achievement of peak plasma concentrations of the drug might coincide with peak airway reactivity in the morning. There have been no clinical trials evaluating the relative efficacy of morning versus evening use. Should be taken at least 2 hours prior to exercise when used for prevention of exercise-induced brohcnospasm.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Morphine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Morphine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Doloral&reg;, Kadian&reg;, M-Eslon&reg;, M.O.S.&reg;, MS Contin&reg;, MS IR&reg;, Statex&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Opiate Analgesic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA I</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, ER Capsule, Injection, Oral Solution, Syrup, Suppository</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>IR: 5, 10, 20, 30 mg, 1, 5, 10, 20 mg/mL. SR: 5, 10, 15, 20, 30, 50, 60, 100, 200. IR Supp: 10, 20, 30 mg. SR Supp: 30, 60, 200, 300 mg. Inj: 1, 2, 5, 15, 25, 50 mg/mL.</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: edema, hypotension/orthostisis. CNS: dizziness, drowsiness, somnolence, headache, insomnia. Derm: itching, rash, sweating, neausea, vomiting. Psych: anxiety, depression. Renal: urinary retention.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Vasodilatory effects thought to be a result of histamine release. More pronounced in hypovolemia and with morphine than other agents.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Naproxen",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Naproxen</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Naprosyn&reg;, Naprosyn SR&reg;, Naprosyn E&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiinflammatory (NSAID)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>RA/OA, short term for inflammation and pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet, Oral Suspesion</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>IR: 250 mg, 375 mg, 500 mg. Enteric coated: 250 mg, 375 mg, 500 mg. SR: 750 mg susp: 25 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily, ER dosed once daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: Edema. CNS: dizziness, headache. Derm: rash. GI: abdominal pain, constipation, heartburn, nausea, peptic ulcer/GI bleed. Heme: bleeding.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with esomeprazole (Vimovo). Modified release formulaitons (ER/EC) not recommended for acute pain. May attenuate effects of antihypertensives, particularly ACE inhibitors and ARBs. Avoid use in renal dysfunction and heart failure. Contraindicated in the last trimester of pregnancy.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Naproxen Sodium",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Naproxen Sodium</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Aleve&reg;, Anaprox&reg;, Anaprox DS&reg;, Naprelan&reg;, Maxidol&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antiinflammatory (NSAID)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL, OTC</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>RA/OA, short term for inflammation and pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>220 mg, 275 mg, 550 mg. ER: 375 mg, 500 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Every 8 Hours, Every 12 Hours, ER dosed once daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: Edema. CNS: dizziness, headache. Derm: rash. GI: abdominal pain, constipation, heartburn, nausea, peptic ulcer/GI bleed. Heme: bleeding.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>220 mg product OTC. May attenuate effects of antihypertensives, particularly ACE inhibitors and ARBs. Avoid use in renal dysfunction and heart failure. Contraindicated in the last trimester of pregnancy.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nifedipine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Nifedipine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Adalat XL&reg;, Adalat PA&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Calcium Channel Blocker (dihydroperidine)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Chronic stable angina, hypertension</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule, ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>XL: 20 mg, 30 mg, 60 mg. IR: 5 mg, 10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: flushing, edema, hypotension. CNS: dizziness, headache. GI: nausea, heartburn.</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with aspirin (Adalat XL Plus). Immediate release nifedipine should not be used to acutely lower blood pressure (risk of CVA, ischemia, acute MI). May cause worsening of heart failure. Drug interactions: CYP 3A4 substrate. Moderate inhibitor of CYP 1A2.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with aspirin (Adalat XL Plus). Immediate release nifedipine should not be used to acutely lower blood pressure (risk of CVA, ischemia, acute MI). May cause worsening of heart failure. Drug interactions: CYP 3A4 substrate. Moderate inhibitor of CYP 1A2.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nitroglycerin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Nitroglycerin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Minitran&reg;, Nitro-Dur&reg;, Transderm-Nitro&reg;, Trinipatch&reg;, Nitroject&reg;, Nitrol&reg;, Nitrolingual&reg;, Nitrostate&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Organic nitrate</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Acute and prention of Indication(s): anginal symptoms, acute hypertension</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Transdermal, Topical Ointment</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>patch: 0.2 mg, 0.4 mg, 0.6 mg, 0.8 mg. Tablet: 0.3 mg, 0.4 mg, 0.6 mg. Spray 0.4 mg. Inj: 0.2 mg/mL. Oint: 2%</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: hypotension. Derm: flushing. CNS: headache, dizziness, lighteheadedness.</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablets are for sublingual use. Tolerance can be prevented by dosing with a nitrate-free period of 10 to 12 hours daily. Patches should be applied to a hariless area on the trunk with sites rotated.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablets are for sublingual use. Tolerance can be prevented by dosing with a nitrate-free period of 10 to 12 hours daily. Patches should be applied to a hariless area on the trunk with sites rotated.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Olanzapine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Olanzapine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Zyprexa&reg; Zyprexa Zydis&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antipsychotic (Atypical)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bipolar disorder, schizophrenia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ODS, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>2.5 mg, 5 mg, 7.5 mg, 10 mg, 15 mg, 20 mg. Inj 10 mg vial</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: somnolence, extrapyramidal symptoms, dizziness, headache, fatigue. Endocrine: increased prolactin. GI: weight gain, increased appetite, constipation, dry mouth.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Injectable olnazapine is administered IM for rapid control of agitation. May have a greater association with hyperglycemia than other atypical antipsychotics. interactions: CYP 2D6 substrate.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Omeprazole",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Omeprazole</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Losec&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Proton Pump Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GERD, hypersecretory conditions, prevention of NSAID induced ulcers</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 20 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Some indications require BID dosing</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. GI: diarrhea, flatulance, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Major substrate and moderate inhibitor of CYP 2C19. Moderate inhibitor of CYP 2C9 and 1A2. Possible association with C. difficile associated diarrhea. May decrease effecacy of clopidogrel, particularly in CYP 2C19 slow metabolizers. May increase risk of osteoporosis-related fractures.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Oxazepam",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oxazepam</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Apo-Oxazepam&reg;, Oxazepam&reg;, (Serax d/c)</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Benzodiazepine</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anxiety, alcohol withdrawal</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 15 mg, 30 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: sedation, amnesia, depression, confusion, dizziness. Resp: respiratory depression (particularly when coadministered with other respiratory depressants). CV: hypotension.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Many unlabelled uses: restless legs syndrome, panic, insomnia. CNS effects enhanced by other CNS depressants. No active heaptic metaboliltes; therefore, less accumulation of effects than with many other benzodiazepines.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Oxycodone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oxycodone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oxycontin&reg;, Oxy.IR&reg;, Oxyneo&reg;, Supedol&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Opiate Analgesic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA I</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>IR: 5 mg, 10 mg, 20 mg. ER: 10 mg, 15 mg, 20 mg, 30 mg, 40 mg, 60 mg, 80 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: dizziness, drowsiness, sedation. GI: constipaiton, nausea, vomiting. Derm: itching. Overdose Adverse Effects: respiratory depression, stupor, hypotension, bradycardia, coma</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with naloxone (Targin) and acetaminophen (Percocet, Endocet). CNS effects enhanced by other CNS depressants. OxyNEO forms a gummy substance that cannot be injected or inhaled.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Oxycodone / Acetaminophen",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oxycodone / Acetaminophen</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Percocet&reg;, Percocet-Demi&reg;, Rivacocet&reg;,Endocet&reg;, Apo-Oxycodone/Acet&reg;, Ratio-Oxycocet&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Opiate Analgesic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CDSA I</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>2.5mg/325mg, 5mg/325mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: dizziness, drowsiness, sedation. GI: constipaiton, nausea, vomiting. Derm: pruritis. Overdose Adverse Effects: respiratory depression, stupor, hypotension, bradycardia, coma</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Overdose or use in combination with other products containing acetaminophen may cause acute acetaminophen toxicity. CNS and Respiratory depression enhanced with concomitant use of other sedative-hypnotics including MAOIs, tri-cyclic antidepressants, benzodiazepines and alcohol. Substrate for CYP 3A4.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pantoprazole",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pantoprazole</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pantolac&reg;, Panto IV&reg;, Tecta&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Proton Pump Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GERD, hypersecretory conditions, prevention of NSAID induced ulcers</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Oral: 20mg, 40mg IV: 40mg powder/vial</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Headache, diarrhea, nausea/vomiting, and general abdominal discomfort.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>May interfere with absorption of drugs where gastric pH is important for bioavailability (e.g. ketoconazole, itraconazole, HIV protease inhibitors), long term use is associated with vitamin B12 deficiency, C. difficile infection and an increased risk of osteoporosis.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Paroxetine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Paroxetine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Paxil&reg;, Paxil CR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, panic disorder, OCD, PTSD, anxiety, PMDD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 20 mg, 30 mg. CR: 12.5 mg, 25 mg, 37.5 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: insomnia, somnolence. GI: nausea, diarrhea, dry mouth. CV: postural hypotension, tachycardia. GU: sexual dysfunction, decreased libido.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: use with caution with other agents that prolong QTc and agents that increase serotonin. Substrate for and inhibitor of CYP 2D6.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Perindopril",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Perindopril</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Coversyl&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angitensin Converting Enzyme Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, heart Indication(s): failure, reduction of CV risk in CAD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>2 mg, 4 mg, 8 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Resp: cough. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment. Angioedema is a rare but severe adverse effect</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with indapamide (Coversyl Plus). Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesarta  efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Phenytoin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Phenytoin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dilantin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticonvulsant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Seizures</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Capsule, Injection, Oral Suspesion, Chewable Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Cap: 30 mg, 100 mg. Chew tab: 50 mg. Susp: 30 mg/5 mL, 125 mg/5mL. Inj: 50 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Three Times Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Derm: rash (rarely Stevens-Johnson), GI: constipation, gingival hyperplasia, nausea, vomiting. CNS (generally dose-related): ataxia, nystagmus, slurred speech. Psych: confusion. Metabolic: associated with vitamin D and folate deficiency.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: substrate for CYP 2C19 and 2C9. Strong inducer of CYP 2B6, 2C19, 2C8, 2C9, 3A4. High potential for precipitation in IV fluids (use inline filter). Absorption impaired when suspension is given with nasogastric feedings (best to withhold the administration of nutritional supplements for 1-2 hours before and after each phenytoin dose).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Prednisone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Prednisone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Deltasone&reg;, Winpred&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Corticosteroid</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Acute inflammation, autoimmune disorders, rheumatologic disorders</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>1 mg, 5 mg, 50 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: hypertension, edema. Derm: atrophic skin changes, impaired healing. Endocrine: adrenal axis suppression, hyperglycemia, hypernatremia, impaired growth. GI: ulceration. Skeletal: osteoporosis. Psych: euphoria, depression.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Discontinuation of long-term therapy (in general >2 weeks; shorter with high dose) required tapering.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pregabalin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pregabalin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Lyrica&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticonvulsant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pain associated with diabetic peripheral neuropathy, pain associated with postherpetic neuralgia, fibromyalgia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mg, 50 mg, 75 mg, 100 mg, 150 mg, 225 mg, 300 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Twice Daily, Three Times Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: peripheral edema. CNS: dizziness, somnolence, ataxia, headache. GI: weight gain, dry mouth. Skeletal: tremor. Ocular: blurred vision, diplopia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: combination with CNS depressants (including alcohol) may enhance toxicity of both agents. There have been postmarketing reports of angioedema and skin reactions.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Quetiapine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Quetiapine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Seroquel&reg;, Seroquel XR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antipsychotic (Atypical)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bipolar disorder, schizophrenia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mg, 100 mg, 200 mg, 300 mg. XR: mg, 150 mg, 200 mg, 300 mg, 400 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet - twice daily extended-release tablet â€“ once daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: orthostatic hypotension, tachycardia. CNS: somnolence, headache, agitation, dizziness, fatigue, extrapyramidal symptoms. Endocrine: increased cholesteorl, LDL, and triglycerides; decreased HDL; hyperglycemia. GI: weight gain, dry mouth, increased appetite, constipation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Elderly patients with dementia-related psychosis treated with antipsychotics are at an increased risk of death compared to placebo. Drug interactions: substrate of CYP 3A4. Avoid in combination with other agents that increase QTc.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rabeprazole sodium",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Rabeprazole sodium</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Pariet&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Proton Pump Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GERD, hypersecretory conditions, prevention of NSAID induced ulcers</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>10 mg, 20 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. GI: diarrhea, flatulance, nausea, vomiting.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablets are enteric coated. Lansoprazole orally disintegrating tablets contain lansoprazole in enteric-coated microgranules. Drug interactions: Major Substrate and moderate inhibitor of CYP 2C19. Possible association with C. difficile associated diarrhea. May decrease effecacy of clopidogrel (may be least likely of the class for this interaction). May increase risk of osteoporosis related fractures.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ramipril",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ramipril</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Altace&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angitensin Converting Enzyme Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, reduce CV mortality post MI, reduction of CV events in high-risk patients</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>1.25 mg, 2.5 mg, 5 mg, 10 mg, 15 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>proton </td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Resp: cough. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment. Angioedema is a rare but severe adverse effect.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with HCTZ (Altace HCT) and felodipine (Altace Plus Felodipine). Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesartan efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ranitidine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Ranitidine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Acid Reducer&reg; (OTC), Nu-Ranit&reg;, Zantac&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Histamine H-2 Receptor Antagonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>OTC / PDL (See column called 'Other')</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Duodenal ulcers, gastric ulcers, heartburn, treatment and prevention of NSAID induced ulcers, GERD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Oral Solution</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>tablet 75 mg, 150 mg, 300 mg, 15 mg/mL. Inj: 25 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: abdominal pain, constipation, diarrhea. CNS: headache.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available OTC in 75 and 150 mg strengths.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Risedronate",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Risedronate</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Actonel&reg; Actonel DR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bisphosphonate</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Osteoporosis, Indication(s): Paget's disease of the bone</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ER Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>5 mg, 30 mg, 35 mg, 75 mg, 150 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Once Weekly, Once Monthly</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Upper GI disorders (dysphagia, esophagitis, esophageal ulcer and gastric ulcer may occur), musculoskeletal pain, abdominal pain, dyspepsia and nausea, diarrhea.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Non DR tablets should be taken on an empty stomach at least 30 minutes before consuming the first food, drink (other than plain water) and/or any other medication of the day. Food, medication or drink other than plain water can interfere with the absorption. DR tablets should be taken with food.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Risperidone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Risperidone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Risperdal&reg;, Risperdal M&reg;, Risperdal Consta&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antipsychotic (Atypical)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Bipolar mania, schizophrenia, autism</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, ODS, Injection, Oral Solution</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.25 mg, 0.5 mg, 1 mg, 2 mg, 3 mg, 4 mg, 1 mg/mL. Inj: 12.5 mg, 25 mg, 37.5 mg, 50 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily, Injection used every 2 weeks</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: orthostatic hypotension, tachycardia. CNS: somnolence, headache, dizziness, fatigue, extrapyramidal symptoms. GI: weight gain, dry mouth, increased appetite, constipation. Derm: rash skeletal: tremor. GU: incontinence.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Elderly patients with dementia-related psychosis treated with antipsychotics are at an increased risk of death compared to placebo. Drug interactions: substrate of CYP 2D6. Avoid in combination with other agents that increase QTc. Injection is long acting for chronic control of symptoms, not acute agitation.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rosuvastatin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Rosuvastatin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Crestor&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antihyperlipidemic Agent (HMG-CoA Reductase Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hyperlipidemia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>5 mg, 10 mg, 20 mg, 40 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Skeletal: musculoseketal pain, rhabdomyolysis (rare), GI: liver funtion abnormalities, nausea, constipation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Use with caution with other agents associated with myopathy/rhabdomyolysis (e.g., fibric acid derivatives). 40 mg dosage contraindicated in combination with niacin or fibric acids.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Salbutamol",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Salbutamol</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Airomir&reg;, Apo-Salvent&reg;, Ventolin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Beta-2 agonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Symptomatic relief and prevention of bronchospasm in asthma, COPD and other bronchopulmonary disorders</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection, Oral Inhaler, DPI, Nebulized</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>MDI: 100 mcg. DPI: 200 mcg. Neb: 2.5 mg/2.5 mL, 2.5 mg/5 mL, 2 mg/mL, 5 mg/mL. Oral: 0.4 mg/mL, 2 mg, 4 mg. I nj: 1 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: tachycardia. Metabolic: hypokalemia. GI: nausea, throat irritation. Neuro: feeling nervous, headache, tremor. Resp: cough.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: avoid combination with beta blockers (particularly noncardioselective). May enhance hypokalemia seen with diuretics.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sennosides",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sennosides</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Senokot&reg;, Senna&reg;, Ex-Lax&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Stimulant Laxative</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>OTC</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Short-term treatment of constipation; evacuate the colon for bowel or rectal exams</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Chewable Tablet, Syrup</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>8.8 mg/5 ml, 8.6 nmg, 15 mg, 25 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Twice Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: abdominal cramps, diarrhea, N/V.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once daily doses should be taken at bedtime; granules may be eaten plain, sprinkled on food, or mixed in liquids. Contraindications: intestinal obstruction, acute intestinal inflammation, colitis ulcerosa, appendicitis Warning: OTC use not recommended for use in patients experiencing stomach pain, N/V, or a sudden change in BM which lasts >2 weeks. NOT recommended for OTC use in children <2 years of age. No drug interactions known. /Available in conbination with docusate.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sertraline",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sertraline</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Zoloft&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, panic disorder, OCD, PTSD, anxiety</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mg, 50 mg, 100 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: insomnia, somnolence. GI: nausea, diarrhea, dry mouth. CV: postural hypotension, tachycardia. GU: sexual dysfunction, decreased libido</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Moderate inhibitor of CYP 2D6, 2C19 and 3A4.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sildenafil",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sildenafil</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Viagra&reg;, Revatio&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDE5 Inhibitor</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Erectile dysfunction, pulmonary hypertension</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet, Injection</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>20 mg, 25 mg, 50 mg, 100 mg. Inj: 0.8 mg/mL</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily (Used on a PRN basis)</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache. Ocular: A small percentage of patients experience visual effects (e.g. impairment of colour discrimination, increased perception to light, blurred vision, eye pain, ocular redness).</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Injection and Revatio product used for pulmonary hypertension is dosed on a TID schedule. Contraindicated in patients taking any form of nitrates (potential for life threatening hypotension). Drug interactions: substrated for CYP 3A4. Concomitant administration of sildenafil to patients taking alpha-blocker therapy may lead to symptomatic hypotension. Priapism has been reportated--any patient experiencing an erection lasting >4 hours should seek emergency medical care.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Simvastatin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Simvastatin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Zocor&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antihyperlipidemic Agent (HMG-CoA Reductase Inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hyperlipidemia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>5 mg, 10 mg, 20 mg, 40 mg, 80 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, taken HS</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Skeletal: musculoseketal pain, rhabdomyolysis (rare), GI: liver funtion abnormalities, nausea, constipation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: substrate for CYP 3A4. Use with caution with other agents associated with myopathy/rhabdomyolysis (e.g., fibric acid derivatives).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Spironolactone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Spironolactone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Aldactone&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diuretic (aldosterone antagonist)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Heart failure, primary aldosteronism, hypokalemia, cirrhosis</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>25 mg, 100 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Dosing Interval is Variable</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Endocrine: gynecomastia. Metabolic: hyperkalemia. CNS: headache, lethargy.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with hydrochlorothizaide (Aldactazide). Drug interactions: Use with caution with other agents associated with hyperkalemia (ACE inhibitors, ARBs, heparain, LMWH, eplerenone, potassium).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tamsulosin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tamsulosin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Flomax CR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Alpha-1 Adrenergic Blocking Agent</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>BPH</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Tablet, ER Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>0.4 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: orthostasis. CNS: headache, dizziness. Resp: rhinitis. GU: abnormal ejaculation.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with dutasteride (Jalyn). Drug interactions: substrate for CYP 3A4. Despite its alpha blocking effects, tamsulosin should not be used as an antihypertensive.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Telmisartan",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Telmisartan</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Micardis&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, reduction of CV events in high-risk patients</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>40mg, 80 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with HCTZ (Micardis Plus) and amlodipine (Twynsta). Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesartan efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Temazepam",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Temazepam</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Restoril&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sedative / Hypnotic (benzodizepine)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Insomnia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>15 mg, 30 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, taken HS</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: drowsiness, fatigue, somnolence, dizziness, hangover. Associated with anterograde amnesia.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Metabolites are inactive and drug accumulation is unlikely. Drug Interactions: combination with CNS depressants (including alcohol) may enhance toxicity of both agents.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tiotropium Bromide",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tiotropium Bromide</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Spiriva&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticholinergic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>COPD</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>DPI</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>18 mcg capsule for inhalation</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>GI: dry mouth. Resp: URI, pharyngitis, sinusitis.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Administered with HandiHaler device.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Trazodone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Trazodone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Trazorel&reg;, Desyrel&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>50 mg, 68.25 mg, 100 mg, 150 mg, 300 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: sedation, headache, dizziness, fatigue. GI: dry mouth, nausea. Ocular: blurred vision. Associated with rare occurrence of priapism with 1/3 of cases requiring surgical intervention.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Insomnia is a common unlabelled use usually at doses lower than antidepressant dosages. Drug interactions: Substrate of CYP 3A4. Induces pglycoprotein.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Valsartan",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Valsartan</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diovan&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonist</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension, reduce CV mortality post MI, heart failure</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>40 mg, 80 mg, 160 mg, 320 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Available in combination with HCTZ (Diovan-HCT). Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesartan efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Valsartan / Hydrochlorothiazide",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Valsartan / Hydrochlorothiazide</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Diovan-HCT&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Angiotensin II Receptor Antagonist / thiazide diuretic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hypertension</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>80 mg/12.5 mg, 160 mg/12.5 mg, 320 mg/12.5 mg, 320 mg/25 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CV: syncope, hypotension. Electrolytes: hyperkalemia. Renal: renal impairment.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: potassium/potassium sparing diuretics, NSAIDs (decreased candesartan efficacy and increased risk of renal dysfunction). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters). Avoid in pregnancy (contraindicated in 2nd and 3rd trimesters).</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Venlafaxine",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Venlafaxine</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Effexor XR&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Antidepressant (selective serotonin and norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor)</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Depression, anxiety, panic disorder</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>ER Capsule</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>37.5 mg, 75 mg, 150 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: headache, somnolence, dizziness, insomnia, anxiety. GI: nausea, dry mouth, anorexia, constipation. GU: abnormal ejaculation. CV: hypertension (dose related), palpitations.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug interactions: Substrate of CYP 3A4 and 2D6. Use with caution with agents that increase serotonin (risk for serotonin syndrome)</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Warfarin",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Warfarin</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Coumadin&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Anticoagulant</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Prophylaxis/treatment of VTE and CVA from cardioembolic causes</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>1 mg, 2 mg, 2.5 mg, 3 mg, 4mg, 5mg, 6mg, 7.5 mg, 10 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Hematologic: bleeding, intraocular hemorrhage. Rare but serious reactions: cholesterol microembolization (purple toes syndrome), tissue necrosis.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Risk factors for bleeding: high intensity anticoagulation (INR >4.0), age â‰¥65, variable INRs, history of GI bleeding, hypertension, cerebrovascular disease, serious heart disease, anemia, malignancy, trauma, renal insufficiency, concomitant drugs Drug interactions: a multitude of interactions resulting from 1) changes in warfarin metabolism, 2) changes in vitamin K metabolism, and 3) displacement from protein binding sites occur. Substrate for CYP 2C9 and minor substrate for 1A2, 2C19, 3A4. Changing vitamin K intake may have a dramatic effect on degree of anticoagulation. Many NHPs interact with warfarin.</td></tr></table>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Zopiclone",
        "answer": "<table><tr><th>Generic Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Zopiclone</td></tr><tr><th>Brand Name:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Rhovane&reg;, Imovane&reg;</td></tr><tr><th>Drug Class:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Sedative / Hypnotic</td></tr><tr><th>Schedule:</th><td class='nodisplay'>PDL</td></tr><tr><th>Indications:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Insomnia</td></tr><tr><th>Dosage Forms:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Tablet</td></tr><tr><th>Strengths:</th><td class='nodisplay'>3.75 ng, 5 mg, 7.5 mg</td></tr><tr><th>Dosing Interval:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Once Daily, Taken HS</td></tr><tr><th>Common Adverse Effects:</th><td class='nodisplay'>CNS: sedation, amnesia, depression, confusion, dizziness.</td></tr><tr><th>Other:</th><td class='nodisplay'>Drug Interactions: Substrate of CYP 2C8 and 3A4. Combination with CNS depressants (including alcohol) may enhance toxicity of both agents.</td></tr></table>"
    }
]